# STUART HAMBLIN

Software Developer

As a former Mechanical Engineer working in the Aerospace industry, I have worked efficiently on teams to complete cost effective projects without compromising safety or airworthiness. In my quest for new knowledge, I am dedicated to solving challenging engineering problems with math, physics, and computer science. My interest in systems engineering stems from my affinity for software development.

# **EDUCATION**

Codeup Projected 2/2019

Certificate of Completion, Java Full Stack Computer Software Engineering

University of Arizona 5/2011

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering/Math Minor

# **SKILLS**

HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, Java, Java EE, MySQL, Vue.js Framework, Spring Boot/MVC, Git Version Control, SolidWorks

#### **PROJECTS**

Personal Website Project 1/2019

Multipage web app with Vue.js framework

Fixer Lister, Codeup 12/2018

Registered users can add/edit/delete ads

Drone Home Project, Startup Weekend 12/2018

Drone photography materialize website

Contacts Manager Project, Codeup 11/2018

Java program to add/edit/delete contacts

Coffee Javascript Project, Codeup 10/2018

Javascript rendered web app with dynamic search

# CONTACT

520-396-8335 / stuart.a.hamblin@gmail.com in/stuart-hamblin github.com/stuartahamblin

#### **EXPERIENCE**

ST Engineering, San Antonio, TX

Mechanical Design Engineer

7/2014-9/2018

Designed cabin wide structural drawings for VIP interiors using GD&T. Performed Engineering Liaison for fabrication/production for Boeing 737/777 aircraft. Design of part installations for 737, 757, 777, 787, A320, A330, A350, and A380. Researched Boeing manuals for Removal/Salvage Documents, and engineering planning.

Southwest Turbine, Phoenix, AZ

Contract Mechanical Engineer 2/2014-5/2014

Designed remanufactured replacement parts (PMA) for Turboprop, Turbofan, and APU gas turbine engines. Compilation of 300+ page FAA data/submittal package for overhaul/repair of a turbine vane.

Expert Aerospace LLC, Phoenix, AZ

Design Engineer

7/2012-12/2013

Designed mechanical aircraft parts providing data substantiation of functions of part features and how they affect the interchangeability/form/fit/function of upper level assemblies in FAA PMA submittals. Compiled metallurgical data to determine suitable alternate materials with heat treatment, applicable surface treatments, and inspections procedures.

Kaman Aerospace, Tucson, AZ

Mechanical Engineer

6/2010-12/2011

Designed mechanical, electromechanical, and electro-optic assemblies in laser measuring systems. Maintained database and technical documents for the JMEWS project. Developed testing/calibration procedures for laser modules.

# LEADERSHIP/SERVICE

Child Advocate of San Antonio (CASA), Camp Thunderbird Wilderness Counselor, Non-profit Camp Wildcat Director/Treasurer/Counselor, TABC Alumni Choir/Counselor, Eagle Scout